[light beachy music]
[轻快的海滩音乐]
♪ ♪
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
- All right, Plankton.
- 好吧，浮游生物。
I managed to fit 12 changes
of underwear
我成功适应了 12 个变化
内衣的
in your suitcase.
在你的手提箱里。
Will that be enough
for the trip?
这样就够了吗
为了旅行？
- [laughing]
- [barking]
- [笑]
- [吠叫]
- I'm gonna be gone
for three days, Karen,
- 我要走了
三天了，凯伦，
so yeah, that should cover it.
所以是的，这应该涵盖它。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
That's right, Spot.
Daddy has to go
没错，斯波特。
爸爸必须走了
to the annual Doomsday Device
Expo in Shell City.
每年一度的世界末日装置
贝壳城世博会。
He's gonna find you
an instrument of ultimate evil.
他会找到你的
终极邪恶的工具。
Yes, he is.
是的，他是。
- [barks]
- Don't worry, boy.
- [吠叫]
- 别担心，男孩。
I left lots of instructions
for Mommy,
我留下了很多指示
对于妈妈来说，
so she knows exactly how
to care for you
所以她知道如何
照顾你
while I'm gone.
当我离开的时候。
[bright orchestral music]
[明亮的管弦乐]
My wittle man just needs wots
of extra wove,
我的机智男人只需要wots
额外的编织，
and I would destroy
the whole world
我会摧毁
整个世界
if anything happened to him.
如果他出了什么事。
[horn honks]
- Oh, your taxi's here.
[喇叭鸣响]
- 哦，你的出租车来了。
♪ ♪
[tires screeching]
[轮胎的尖叫声]
Off you go, Sheldon.
你走吧，谢尔顿。
- So long, Karen.
- 再见，凯伦。
Bye, Spotty!
再见，斯帕蒂！
- Bye, Plankton.
- 再见，浮游生物。
Have a nice trip.
旅行愉快。
Looks like it's just you
and me, Spot.
看来只有你一个人
还有我，斯波特。
Spot?
- [barking]
点？
- [吠叫]
[alarm blares]
[警报声]
Oh, Plankton's instructions.
哦，浮游生物的指示。
Spot, bad amoeba.
现货，坏阿米巴原虫。
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
- Oh, who needs
Plankton's little notes?
- 哦，谁需要
浮游生物的小笔记？
A sophisticated AI like myself
should have no problem
像我这样复杂的人工智能
应该没问题
with a simple organic being.
与一个简单的有机存在。
All he needs
is a basic analysis.
他所需要的一切
是一个基本的分析。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[laser humming]
[激光嗡嗡声]
- [chomps]
- No!
- [咀嚼]
- 不！
I'm not done analyzing you.
- [barks]
我还没分析完你呢。
- [吠叫]
- Spot! Heel, boy.
- 点！脚后跟，男孩。
Heel.
- [barks, pants]
脚跟。
- [吠叫，裤子]
[squish]
[挤压]
- Uh-oh.
- 呃哦。
Is he supposed to do that?
他应该这样做吗？
Hmm, maybe he needs
a little pumping up.
嗯，也许他需要
有点泵气。
[light music]
[轻音乐]
♪ ♪
- [squeaking]
- [grunts]
- [吱吱声]
- [咕哝]
[straining]
[紧张]
There you go, Spot.
- [barks]
就这样吧，斯波特。
- [吠叫]
[splat]
[啪嗒]
- Aah!
- 啊啊！
I killed him!
我杀了他！
[pounding at door]
[敲门]
Huh?
啊？
[gasps]
[喘气]
Who sent you?
谁派你来的？
What do you know?
你知道什么？
- Hi, Karen.
- 嗨，凯伦。
Gary has a playdate with Spot,
remember?
加里和 Spot 有个约会，
还记得吗？
- Meow.
- 喵。
- Uh, oh, with Spot, huh?
- 呃，哦，用 Spot 吧？
[laughs nervously]
Well, uh, the thing is,
[紧张地笑]
嗯，呃，问题是，
Spot can't play today
because he's, uh--
今天现场无法播放
因为他是，呃——
he--busy. He's busy.
他——忙。他很忙。
He's, uh, very busy, um...
[dial-up beeps]
他，呃，很忙，嗯……
[拨号嘟嘟声]
All over the place in bits
and pieces
到处都是点点滴滴
和碎片
because I exploded him.
因为我把他炸了。
[wailing, crying]
[哀号，哭泣]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Yeah, that's Spot all right.
是的，那就是 Spot。
[laughing]
[笑]
- Huh?
- 啊？
- Spot, come to SpongeBob!
- 现货，来海绵宝宝吧！
[whistles]
[口哨声]
[cheery music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- How did you figure that out?
- 你是怎么想出来的？
- This happens all the time
when he plays with Gary.
- 这种情况经常发生
当他和加里一起玩的时候。
- [squeals]
- [grunts]
- [尖叫声]
- [咕哝]
- [squeals]
- Meow.
- [尖叫声]
- 喵。
- Oh, I admit,
looking after Spot
- 哦，我承认，
照顾现货
while Plankton is gone
is proving trickier
当浮游生物消失时
事实证明更棘手
than I thought.
比我想象的要多。
♪ ♪
[crunch]
[紧缩]
- Whoo!
- 呼！
[squealing]
[尖叫声]
- Maybe he needs
to burn off some energy?
- 也许他需要
消耗一些能量？
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
How are you so strong?
你怎么这么强？
♪ ♪
[sighs]
- [barks]
[叹气]
- [吠叫]
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
[purrs]
[呼噜声]
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
[belches]
[打嗝]
[sizzling]
[嘶嘶声]
- Meow?
- 喵？
[brakes screeching]
[刹车声]
- Spot, look at this mess.
- 斑点，看看这烂摊子。
- Come on, Spot.
- 来吧，斯波特。
Don't you want
to be a good boy like Gary?
难道你不想
做一个像Gary一样的好孩子？
[siren blares]
- [growls]
[警笛声]
- [咆哮]
- [belches]
- [打嗝]
[barking]
- Spot, no!
[吠叫]
- 现货，不！
Bad boy.
坏男孩。
- Whoa!
- [barking]
- 哇！
- [吠叫]
- [sobbing]
- [gasps]
- [抽泣]
- [喘气]
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- [chomps]
- [咀嚼]
- I nose this ain't my donut.
- 我嗅到这不是我的甜甜圈。
- Oh.
- 哦。
[chokes]
[窒息]
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
- He's too fast.
- 他太快了。
How can this get any worse?
这怎么会变得更糟呢？
[phone rings]
[电话铃声]
- Karen's head,
how may I direct your call?
- 凯伦的头，
我该如何转接您的电话？
- Oh, yes.
May I talk to Karen?
- 哦是的。
我可以和凯伦谈谈吗？
Wait a minute. Who is this?
等一下。这是谁？
- Uh, uh, that was me...
[laughs]
- 呃，呃，那是我……
[笑]
Throwing my voice,
and now it's you.
发出我的声音，
现在是你了。
How's the Doomsday Expo?
末日博览会怎么样？
- Oh, it's over.
- 哦，结束了。
I'm coming home early.
- You're what?
我要早点回家
- 你是什么？
- But I bought the most evil
world-conquering device
- 但我买了最邪恶的
征服世界的装置
I could find.
我能找到。
[spooky music]
[诡异的音乐]
Anyway, how's my little Spot?
无论如何，我的小斑点怎么样？
Put him on the phone.
让他接电话。
I miss his voice.
我想念他的声音。
- Put Spot on the phone?
- Whoa.
- 在手机上安装 Spot 吗？
- 哇哦。
This phone?
- [whimpers]
这个电话？
- [呜咽]
Ooh.
哦。
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
- There's my wittle man.
- 这是我的机智人。
Sounds like Mommy is taking
good care of you.
听起来妈妈正在服用
照顾好你。
- Hey, some idiot left
this tiny suitcase
- 嘿，剩下一些白痴
这个小手提箱
next to an open flame!
旁边有明火！
[explosions]
Oh, no.
[爆炸]
哦，不。
[everyone screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- Uh, gotta go.
- 呃，该走了。
[tense music]
[紧张的音乐]
♪ ♪
[bell dings]
[铃声]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Whew, let's get back
before Plankton comes home.
哇，我们回去吧
在浮游生物回家之前。
- Meow.
- Oh, hey, Gary.
- 喵。
- 哦，嘿，加里。
How was your shift?
- Meow.
你的轮班怎么样？
- 喵。
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
- What's wrong?
- 怎么了？
You haven't touched your chum.
你还没有碰过你的密友。
- No, thank you.
- 不，谢谢。
I don't really eat chum.
我真的不吃密友。
- Yep, me neither.
- 是的，我也一样。
- [growling, barking]
- [咆哮，吠叫]
- Karen? Have you fed Spot yet?
- 凯伦？你喂Spot了吗？
- No, does he not consume
power from his battery?
- 不，他不消费吗
从他的电池供电？
- Uh, no.
- 呃，不。
He consumes other stuff.
他消耗其他东西。
- [sniffs]
- [嗅嗅]
[barks]
[吠叫]
- Are you still hungry?
- [barks]
- 你还饿吗？
- [吠叫]
- Okay, how 'bout a nice, um,
a napkin dispenser?
- 好吧，怎么样，嗯，
餐巾纸分配器？
- [gulps]
- [吞咽]
- Gee, Spot'll eat anything,
huh?
- 哎呀，Spot什么都吃，
嗯？
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
- [gasps, growls]
No more, Spot.
- [喘气，咆哮]
不用了，斯波特。
You literally just ate us
out of house and home.
你简直把我们吃了
出家门和家。
- [barks]
- [吠叫]
- Fine, you're still hungry?
- 好吧，你还饿吗？
I'll give you all
the nourishment
我会给你一切
营养
you'll ever need.
你永远需要。
Here, I synthesized
a perpetual nutrient pill.
这里我综合一下
永久营养丸。
It'll keep feeding you
so you'll be full.
它会一直喂你
这样你就会吃饱了。
Forever.
永远。
Huh? Uh--
啊？呃——
- Hey, Karen?
- 嘿，凯伦？
Is he supposed
to be getting bigger?
他是否应该
变得更大？
- That was not
in my calculations.
- 那不是
在我的计算中。
- It's gonna stop soon? Right?
- Meow.
- 很快就会停止吗？正确的？
- 喵。
- Uh, well,
you see, SpongeBob,
- 呃，好吧，
你看，海绵宝宝，
I didn't program the pill
to stop.
我没有对药丸进行编程
停止。
Ever.
曾经。
[creaking]
[吱吱作响]
- I gotta be careful with you.
[laughs]
- 我得小心你。
[笑]
One wrong move and you'll blow
the whole ocean sky-high.
一个错误的举动就会让你大吃一惊
整个海洋高耸入云。
[laughs]
[笑]
Huh?
啊？
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
Huh, the good times never last.
呵呵，美好的时光永远不会长久。
Aah!
啊啊！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[boom]
- Ouch!
[轰]
- 哎呀！
♪ ♪
- [gasps]
- Huh?
- [喘气]
- 啊？
[citizens murmuring]
[市民窃窃私语]
- Karen!
- 凯伦！
- [grunts]
- None of my sticky notes said
- [咕哝]
- 我的便利贴都没有说
to turn Spot into a behemoth!
将 Spot 变成庞然大物！
- Well,
this wouldn't have happened
- 嗯，
这不会发生
if you had trained him
properly.
如果你训练过他
正确地。
- I'm a busy man.
- 我是个大忙人。
You should've been following
my instructions.
你应该一直在关注
我的指示。
- Excuse me?
- 打扰一下？
I am your computer wife,
not your computer maid.
我是你的电脑老婆
不是你的电脑女仆。
- [whining]
- I slave all day
- [抱怨]
- 我整天都在做奴隶
over a hot keyboard--
- Oh, so everything
在热键盘上——
- 哦，所以一切
is my fault!
是我的错！
It's all ones and zeroes
with you, honey.
都是一和零
和你在一起，亲爱的。
You probably made Spot bigger
than me on purpose...
你可能让 Spot 变得更大
故意比我...
- Aha!
- To make me feel small.
- 啊哈！
- 让我感觉自己很渺小。
- Spot?
- Your mouth is the biggest
- 点？
- 你的嘴是最大的
part of you--
- Ah!
你的一部分——
- 啊！
- Everything about you
is small.
- 关于你的一切
很小。
- My heart is big.
- 我的心很大。
- [straining]
- I should not have settled.
- [紧张]
- 我不应该安顿下来。
- Look!
both: Huh?
- 看！
两人：啊？
- [barking]
- [吠叫]
- Spot!
- 点！
I think he's dividing.
我认为他正在分裂。
- Aww, he doesn't like it
when Mommy and Daddy fight.
- 哇哦，他不喜欢
当妈妈和爸爸吵架的时候。
Come on, boy. Come to Papa.
- [groaning]
来吧，男孩。来找爸爸吧。
- [呻吟]
- Come on, boy!
- Come to Daddy.
- 来吧，孩子！
- 到爸爸那里来。
- Come on!
- [groaning]
- 快点！
- [呻吟]
[snap]
[折断]
all: Spot!
全体：现货！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Aww. [laughs]
哇。 [笑]
Aww.
- Oh, I can't stay mad
哇。
- 哦，我不能继续生气
at these cute little faces.
看着这些可爱的小脸。
- Well,
I'm still a little mad.
- 嗯，
我还是有点生气。
[both laugh]
- Aww.
[两人都笑了]
- 哇。
- [chomps]
- [laughing]
- [咀嚼]
- [笑]
[playful music]
[俏皮的音乐]
♪ ♪
[sizzling]
[嘶嘶声]
[light beachy music]
[轻快的海滩音乐]
♪ ♪